[THEME MUSIC PLAYING]
[SCREAMING IN PAIN]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
- [ENGINE REVVING]
- [TIRES SCREECHING]
[TIRES SCREECH]
[ENGINES REVVING]
[TRUCK HORN BLARES]
[LOUD CRASH]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
- Stop!
- [GUNSHOTS]
[FIREWORKS EXPLODING]
[METAL RODS CLANGING]
- [ENGINE REVVING]
- [BUS HORN HONKS]
[GLASS SHATTERING]
- [TIRES SCREECHING]
- [LOUD CRASH]
[ENGINES REVVING]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[GUNSHOTS]
- [TRUCK HORN HONKS]
- [LOUD CRASH]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
The law is the law.
If someone breaks it,
they must be held accountable!
There are things that we do
that are often
not in accordance with the law.
But they're necessary.
The mission was still a success.
We caught Mr. Chan.
We are one team.
We will continue to support
each other until the end.
- I'll get back at them, Ma.
- Forget about Mr. Chan for now.
I'm not talking about Mr. Chan.
But the one who shot me!
Someone else was there
that made it easier for us
to catch Mr. Chan.
The question is, who was it?
- Here's the gold.
- It's all here.
In a moment of temptation,
a person's true character
and principles show.
I have the money for
Papa's medicine and surgery.
Thank you so much
for keeping your promise.
The surgery was successful.
Let's just wait for him
to wake up.
[JAIL GATE CREAKS]
[PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING]
[POLICE] Sign here.
Mr. Chan!
Victor! Nice to see you,
but not here.
How did you get caught?
This agent, lady agent,
very good acting!
She fooled me!
Pretend to be my buyer!
- Which agent?
- Sam. Sam...
Jacinto! Sam Jacinto!
That woman's taking us out
one by one.
She won't stop until
I get pinned on this case.
No, Victor.
She's not the reason.
She did not catch me.
This guy? Long hair guy,
- jacket, he caught me.
- Stay here, stay here.
- Go away from there.
- Not Jacinto, not the girl.
Go inside.
- Hey! Hey! Hey, you!
- [JAIL GATE CLANGING]
I need my phone call!
[VICTOR] It's him again.
Why is he so dead set
on catching us?
Once I get out of here,
I'll find that bastard,
and make him pay.
[CHAN] I need to talk my lawyer!
I want call! Hey!
Hey!
[JAIL GATE CLANGING]
Hey, hey! Hey! Hey!
[DEBORAH] Mariano.
Just a minute.
Go on.
[PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING]
After 20 years,
Ricardo and I will meet again.
I'll show him the new Mariano.
I am one with you
in confronting Ricardo.
I'm also angry
with his daughter.
I'm angry with all aggravations
affecting our business.
However, are you truly ready
to start a war
against the police?
[PENSIVE MUSIC CONTINUES]
I'm not scared of them.
Once we start a war,
there's no turning back.
Do you really want
to do this now?
[PENSIVE MUSIC CONTINUES]
Now, when Victor's in jail...
And Lucas is still healing?
Don't worry.
I'll do what is right.
[MUSIC INTENSIFYING]
[MUSIC ENDS]
[CRICKETS CHIRPING IN DISTANCE]
[LINE RINGING]
[PHONE RINGING]
[PHONE BEEPS]
Yes, General?
Good evening, Dir. Delgado.
I would like to talk to you
about Samantha and the NCIA.
What about...
the NCIA and Sam would you
like to talk about?
Well, Director, I understand.
I can see that you have
a lot of confidence in Samantha.
Because you let her handle
the gold smuggling case.
But I heard she's up against
a very powerful syndicate.
General, she's like a
daughter to me.
Let me be frank, General.
You're being harsh on her.
Harsh? What do you mean harsh?
She's under too much pressure
to please you,
so much that
she's losing focus at work.
There are things
she could have fixed
or corrected, but...
instead she worries
about earning your approval.
Such as? Director, please.
Please tell me, because
I just want to know if...
the blame is on me,
or if I'm crossing the line.
[MOROSE MUSIC PLAYING]
Sam acted on her own,
even though I forbade it,
to catch those connected
to the syndicate.
A shootout broke out.
And, uh...
one of them was injured.
But they were all safe
and caught the criminal.
[MOROSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
Thank you for telling me.
General...
Sam needs a father
who will guide her.
She desperately needs you.
Thank you.
[PHONE BEEPS]
[MANNY] Boss.
I've already had the clubhouse
manager sign the NDA form.
Whatever you discuss here,
it's gonna be confidential.
Good.
And by the way, Manny...
Double the security.
I don't trust the person
we're meeting later.
No problem, sir.
Let's go, Toto.
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
[MUSIC ENDS]
[MAX] Hi, Ma.
Where's Dad?
[ISOBEL] I...
...don't know.
[INHALES DEEPLY]
He left without telling me
where he was going.
[SIGHS]
Ma...
I'm sorry.
[SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING]
I know I've failed this family
in many ways.
[INHALES SHARPLY]
And recently,
things have been such a mess.
[MAX SNIFFLES]
And I want you to know...
that I understand
where you're coming from.
- [SOMBER MUSIC CONTINUES]
- [INHALES DEEPLY]
You know, I've delivered
the world peace answer
in pageants
so many times before.
But this time, I really mean it.
I want peace...
...for our family.
Don't worry, Ma.
I'll make it up to you.
[SOMBER MUSIC CONTINUES]
Actually...
I think I already did.
What do you mean?
Do you remember that woman
from the news?
The wife of the gunshot victim?
I went to see her and...
gave her some money.
You mean, it's already settled?
[MAX] Well, I think...
I think we're getting there.
The family is still being
stubborn, especially the son.
But this woman...
I think I've won her over.
And she can help us
fix this mess.
That's good.
[SOMBER MUSIC CONTINUES]
[ENGINES RUMBLING]
[CAR DOOR CLOSES]
[HURRIED FOOTSTEPS]
[CAR DOOR OPENS]
[UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING]
[CAR DOOR CLOSES]
Sir, you can't bring your guns.
[TOTO] Sir Manny,
they're coming up now.
Just leave the big ones.
- Sir.
- Yes, sir.
[UNSETTLING MUSIC CONTINUES]
Wait a minute.
We have a meeting
with Gen. Ricardo Jacinto.
Are you Mariano Zafra?
I am.
You're the only one allowed in.
No.
We need to stay with him.
Gen. Jacinto's order was clear.
Mariano Zafra's the only one
allowed inside.
It's alright.
Just wait for me here.
Sir, if any problem comes up,
we'll be right here.
Don't worry, he
won't touch me.
Pat him down.
There's no need for that.
[GUN CLATTERS]
Happy now?
Let's go.
[UNSETTLING MUSIC CONTINUES]
General Jacinto is right there.
[MARIANO] Ricardo.
Long time no see.
It's been a long time.
I can just call you Ricardo,
right?
After all,
we're both retired now.
Call me anything you want.
Sit down.
[UNSETTLING MUSIC CONTINUES]
What do you want?
[MARIANO] I'll cut to the chase.
You know why I'm here.
As I said before,
I have no control over
my daughter Samantha.
I already talked to her,
but she won't listen.
What does your daughter want?
Does she want money,
cars, a house?
I can give all of that to her!
Not to be arrogant,
but we can give those to her.
But you don't get it.
Bribery won't work on her.
So, this means that
you won't help me?
So you're saying
that Samantha
won't help my son?
I'm sorry.
[UNSETTLING MUSIC CONTINUES]
You were a General.
You had control over
the whole police force!
Now, you can't even
order around your own child
who holds a low rank?
You useless father!
[THUDS]
Who the hell
do you think you are
to question about how
I raise my daughters?
Your son is a criminal.
You are the reason why
he's in jail right now.
He's just like you.
You've always had
the mindset of a criminal!
This "hoodlum brain"
you're talking about
is the one who helped you get
everything you wanted before!
You gained all of this wealth
because of me!
I hope you never
forgot about that.
Or maybe you need me
to remind you.
And now you're threatening me?
Don't.
Even though I retired,
I'm still a General, Mariano.
I still have my own connections
and influence.
And that's called power.
Was your family
business successful?
Don't mess with me.
Your group and your family
are going to pay for this.
So don't you ever cross me.
This will be the last time
we'll see each other.
- Let's go.
- [GRUNTS]
[UNSETTLING MUSIC CONTINUES]
Sir.
How did it go?
Let's go.
[RICARDO] Does Mariano think
that he has control over me
because he knows my past?
I won't let that happen.
Come to think of it,
he benefited from this too.
[UNSETTLING MUSIC CONTINUES]
- I'll fix this.
- [DOOR OPENS]
[CLEARS THROAT] Dad.
Where's Sam?
I don't know.
Maybe she's still at work.
Dad, why do you seem angry?
Where were you?
It doesn't matter where I was.
What's important
is I talk to your sister.
She has crossed the line.
Oh, Ricardo.
What is this about again?
Is there a problem?
Maybe we can fix it together.
I'll handle it, Isobel.
Knowing you, you can't
discipline your daughter.
[RICARDO SIGHS DEEPLY]
[PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING]
[YOUNG RICARDO]
File a police report.
Homicide and robbery.
No one else must know
about what happened, Mariano.
We will carry this secret
to our graves.
[YOUNG MARIANO] Yes, sir.
You can count on it.
Sir.
Since Rudy's gone,
can I get my share?
Sure. Take that.
That's your share.
And that's a little bonus.
Sir, don't you think
that's a little unfair to me?
I've done so much for you.
Unfair? Why? Did you
invest money in this?
You didn't.
Mariano, just be thankful
I gave you a share.
Don't forget the police report.
[GRIM MUSIC PLAYING]
I'll make you pay one day,
you bastard.
[GRIM MUSIC CONTINUES]
I know what you're thinking.
You've waited so long for this.
To get back at Ricardo
for everything he did to you.
He abused and belittled me.
But with the little gold
he spared me,
we were able to start
our business and grow it.
You don't have to rush.
Let him think
that he's still in control.
Mm.
You'll have your
glory days soon.
The tides will turn
to our favor.
Why is your dad
in a bad mood again?
For sure, Sam did
something again.
Don't worry, Ma.
I'll talk to Sam.
I just hope she listens
and we don't get
into another fight.
"Another fight?"
I told her off last night
for talking back at Dad.
Goodness!
You're all stressing me out!
There she is.
Hey, Sam.
- Sam.
- Mom.
What did you do this time?
- W-Wait--
- Is there a problem?
Max, I got this.
Sam, what happened?
Your dad is looking for you.
When I asked why,
he wouldn't tell me.
What's going on?
Maybe he already got wind
of what happened.
I wasn't planning on
hiding what I did to him.
What did you do?
- Well, you see--
- [RICARDO] Samantha?
Samantha!
[MOROSE MUSIC PLAYING]
Dad...
You broke the protocol
of your agency?!
Is that true?!
I want to hear it from you.
It's true.
No law enforcer
in their right mind
would conduct an operation
without his superior's
knowledge.
You've been warned!
But, Dad, we only did that
to catch the members
of the gold-smuggling syndicate.
In fact, we managed
to catch Mr. Chan!
We're so close
to solving the case.
You think you're that good?
You're going against
a big syndicate.
You're showing off at the
expense of your colleagues.
Is that it?!
Dad, that's not true.
You keep saying
you'll make it up to us.
You think ruining my name
is the best way to do so?
Ricardo, can we talk about this
once you've calmed down?
Ma, you don't understand.
What she did is equivalent
to insubordination.
Do you know the importance
of the name you're carrying?
You're ruining my legacy!
But I will give you
one more chance
because your mom asked me...
...to act more
like a father to you.
But if you do something again
to tarnish my name,
I won't kick you out.
I'll forget you're my daughter.
Ricardo!
[MOROSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
[SOFT MUSIC PLAYING]
[DRAWER OPENS]
[DRAWER CLOSES]
[SAM SIGHS]
Maybe I should really
just drop this Zafra case.
[SAM SIGHS]
[INHALES DEEPLY] No.
I can't give up on this case.
I need to strengthen the case
so I can hold
everyone involved accountable.
For our nation.
[SAM BREATHES DEEPLY]
[SOFT MUSIC CONTINUES]
Thank you, Gabo,
for all your help.
If it weren't for you,
your father wouldn't
have gotten the surgery.
- You didn't let him down.
- [GABO SIGHS]
Auntie,
I wouldn't let anything bad
happen to Papa.
I would do everything
to keep him alive.
But really, thank you so much.
I don't know what I'd do
if we lost your dad.
[VOICE SHAKING] Thank you, Gabo.
Auntie Betchay...
I lost my mother
at an early age.
I can't lose Papa either.
[GENTLE MUSIC PLAYING]
[WHEELS RATTLING]
Oh, there he is. There he is.
- Rudy.
- Pa.
How are you feeling?
[NURSE] Excuse me.
Nurse, please be gentle.
He might get hurt.
Come on, slowly.
- Gently.
- Gently, please.
- [NURSE] Get up slowly, sir.
- Slowly, Pa.
[NURSE] Slowly, sir.
Slowly, Pa.
- [MAMENG] Don't hurry.
- Slowly, slowly.
[GABO] Slowly, Pa.
There you go.
[RUDY BREATHES DEEPLY]
How do you feel?
A bit...
better, son.
Don't worry, Pa.
You'll be discharged soon.
[BETCHAY] Oh, Doc.
- Good day.
- How's it going? Any updates?
The patient's stats
and progress are good.
We're expecting
a quick recovery.
And if this continues,
he can go home in no time.
Doctor, can we take him home
so he can recover there?
You can do that.
You just need
to sign the waiver.
- I'll get going.
- Thank you.
Pa, did you hear that?
You will be home soon.
You know what,
Gabo managed to get money
to pay for your surgery.
Son, I want to go home.
Uh, sure. I'll pack your things.
- I'll go handle the paperwork.
- Yes.
Come on, come on.
Let's go, Dante.
[GABO SIGHS]
[GENTLE MUSIC CONTINUES]
I am so happy that your
surgery went well,
and I hope that your recovery
goes smoothly.
Gabo, tell me the truth.
Did you do anything
illegal?
Where did you get the money?
[MOROSE MUSIC PLAYING]
No, Pa.
I took on a job...
and that's where
I got the money.
It's from a job
that I did.
I accepted it to have
money for your surgery.
What exactly did you do
to get that money?
[MOROSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
Someone asked me to do
a job for them.
He was a fellow inmate.
I was surprised...
when I saw him
and his group.
They were the ones
who gave me the job.
They asked me...
to get something
for them.
I was paid to get gold.
That's how I was able
to pay for your surgery.
Gold?
[MOROSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
I'll be honest, Pa.
When I got the gold...
I had second thoughts...
about giving it
to them.
The truth is...
that gold can change
our lives.
We can live
a lavish life, Pa.
We can buy anything
we want.
But, Pa...
I felt guilty.
And I thought of you.
Even though I knew I won't
earn that much...
I decided to
do the right thing.
It made me think
of you, Pa.
You did that?
You gave up the gold?
Please don't be mad
at me.
I did it because I knew
it was the right thing to do.
I'm not mad.
I'm so happy
to hear that.
I'm very happy.
[HOPEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
Pa...
I know we'll get
through this.
I know that no matter
what happens,
and whatever challenges
we face...
we can overcome
all of them.
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
Thank you, son.
[HOPEFUL MUSIC CONTINUES]
If you find that treasure,
we'll split it between us.
Rudy took everything!
I told you not to trust
that bastard!
Find him.
I don't care
wherever he is!
If you come with me,
The conflict of the past...
That gold is the reason
we lost everything.
...will bring chaos
to the present.
He has to pay
for what he did to my mother.
I need to find him!